Yidnekachew (Yidne) Tafese | QA Engineer

Summary

5+ years of full suite software QA testing, developing & executing high-level test strategies & test cases. Experienced in manual & regression testing, as well as writing & running automated test scripts. Proven organizational & time management skills & ability to work independently while being a collaborative team player delivering high quality work

Personal

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia | yedu24@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/yidnekac hew-tafese-71442089/

Education

Ambo University - Ethiopia | 2011-2015 | BS, Information Technology | 13th ranked university in Ethiopia

Areas of Expertise

Windows OS, Android, iOS
Agile (Scrum, Kanban)
Manual & Automation Testing
API Testing
Mobile Application Testing
Test Case Development
Functional, Non-Functional &
Regression Testing
Defect & Data Management
Test Management & Planning

Tools & Skills

Office 365
Selenium, Test NG, Appium, Test-Iin
Postman, Swagger
Microsoft Azure DevOps
Trello, Jira, Kapptivate, Android Studio,
Playwright, Katalon Stidio,
Python, JavaScript, Java, C#, SQL
Critical & Analytical Thinking
Time Management Skills
Work Efficiently in a Fast-Paced,
Startup Environment
Strong Written & Verbal
Communication

Experience

Getwelp Limited | London, UK (Remote) | June 2022 - Present QA Lead Engineer for Luna Trainer web & mobile app

- Responsible for the planning, development, and execution of the overall Quality Assurance strategy, creating and executing manual and automated Selenium test cases, while defining quality standards for dog trainer CRM application
- Drive Quality Assurance initiatives and process improvements, and testing cloud applications, communicating & identifying major status updates & customer concerns to the VP of engineering
- Authored weekly status reports & applied excellent escalation skills, establishing relationships and responsibilities within a team of 8 engineers, 2 UX designers, & Chief Product Officer
- Utilized Selenium Web-driver IO, Linear, iOS, Android, Postman, Slack, Office 365

Perago Info Systems | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia | Sept 2016 – Sept 2021 QA Engineer for Electronic Government Procurement(e-GP), Green Legacy

- Responsible for planning, development, and execution of the overall Quality Assurance strategy, creating and executing test cases while adhering to established software quality standards in general for measuring software quality
- Drove Quality Assurance initiatives and process improvements and testing on-premise and Cloud applications
- Monitored other QA staff members of the software Quality Assurance organization and communicated major status of the project, QA personnel, and customer concerns to the QA Manager
- Delivered weekly status reports, and applied excellent escalation skills, established relationships and responsibilities within a team of 15 QA engineers, providing continuous technology support for clients
- Conducted Training & Capacity building for clients
- Utilized Microsoft Windows, Microsoft Trello, Microsoft Azure DevOps, Selenium, Jira, Appium, SQL, Postman, Testlink, Swagger